<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel>
<title>Verstappen.nl - News</title>
<link>http://www.verstappen.nl/</link>
<description>Verstappen.nl - News</description>
<atom:link href="http://www.verstappen.nl/rss/nieuwsen.php" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<image>
	<url>http://www.verstappen.nl/images/max_logo.png</url>
	<title>Verstappen.nl - News</title>
	<link>http://www.verstappen.nl/</link>
</image>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a signed cap and flag!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2516&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen webshop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which a personally by Max signed Dutch cap (priced at &euro; 34,95) and Dutch flag (priced at &euro; 15,00) can be won during this sixth round of the season. These products and other Max Verstappen and Red Bull merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 May 2016 21:25:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Formule_1_GP_Belgie_-_Spa-Francorchamps/DSCF5170-23c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2516&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max and F1 colleagues win charity football match </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2515&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen is not only good at racing cars at high speeds, the Dutchman is also pretty good at football. The Red Bull driver had a chance to show off his quick feet at the annual pre-Monaco GP charity match.</p>

<p>As usual, the match was held in Monte Carlo&#39;s Stade Louis II and was organised by prince Albert of Monaco. Max took to pitch as part of a team of F1 drivers with Sebastian Vettel, Fernando Alonso, Felipe Massa, Pascal Wehrlein and Carlos Sainz all part of the line-up.</p>

<p>The drivers were up against an All-Stars team, headed by the prince Albert and trained by Claudio Ranieri. MotoGP legends Max Biaggi and Loris Capirossi iwhere among the stars in the prince&#39;s team.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 24 May 2016 20:53:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Liefdadigheids_Voetbalwedstrijd_-_Monaco/Monaco_football_charity_(6)-6f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2515&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "We will see what happens in Monaco"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2514&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max is looking forward to his second race for Red Bull Racing, in Monaco: &quot;I always enjoy racing street circuits like Monaco because you are really pushing the limit and are very close to the walls, it gives you a great feeling that you are on top of your car and getting the most out of it.&quot;</p>

<p>&ldquo;It&rsquo;s so difficult to overtake in Monaco, last year I tried and we ended up in the wall, so the most important thing is to have a good qualifying and start and from there on keep it on the track! Monaco is also special because the track is walking distance from where I live so that&rsquo;s nice to feel like I&rsquo;m home during the race weekend.&nbsp;Naturally there is a lot more attention around driving the car but at the end the most important thing for the driver is just to focus on what you&rsquo;re doing.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 May 2016 17:07:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Testdagen_-_Barcelona/P-20160518-00714_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-35c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2514&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max signs with Exact as Tech Talent Leader</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2513&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Exact announced today that Max Verstappen, the youngest Formula 1 winner ever, will join the company as a Tech Talent Leader. Verstappen&rsquo;s involvement with the Dutch tech company begins on June 1, 2016 and will focus on inspiring some of the company&rsquo;s most promising tech talent.</p>

<p>With Verstappen&rsquo;s rapidly evolving racing career, Exact sees opportunity to benefit from his personal character and story as a unique way to coach the talent within the company. As an exceptional advisor to Exact&rsquo;s HR Board, Verstappen will symbolize the importance of creating the right environment to allow young talent to flourish.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 20 May 2016 06:53:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/CAP_0882-2f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2513&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Rocquelin of RBR: "Good program of work completed"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2512&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen took over in the Red Bull Racing RB12 for the second and final day of 2016&rsquo;s first in-season test. Max had a busy day at the Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya, completing 118 laps, running with tyres and a setup similar to those used for the Spanish Grand Prix at the weekend. He finished Wednesday P1 on the timesheet, 0.739s ahead of his nearest rival. Of much greater significance, he completed his program with no reliability issues.&nbsp;</p>

<p>Max carried on the aero development work started Tuesday by Daniel Ricciardo. His program, however, had the additional target of getting the driver comfortable in the car and comfortable with his crew. Despite having already won a Grand Prix in the RB12, Max is still getting to know the car, and thus the great benefit of the test day was allowing him to fine-tune his setup preferences and develop relationships with his engineers and crew.&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 19 May 2016 09:19:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Testdagen_-_Barcelona/P-20160518-00155_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-13e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2512&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max Verstappen rounds up test day as the fastest: "I enjoyed it again"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2511&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen rounded up the second day of Formula 1-testing in Barcelona as the fastest one on track. The brand new Grand Prix-winner did his fastest lap, a 1:23.267 just before lunch already, on a set of the soft compound tyres. Stoffel Vandoorne, in his McLaren, came in second. However, the Belgian did this on a set of the super softs. Pascal Wehrlein, driving the Mercedes for this test, clocked the third time. The German did his fastest time in the afternoon.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I enjoyed it again today&rdquo;, Max shares with Verstappen.nl. &ldquo;We were able to do some very good mileage and the car is very good to drive.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 May 2016 17:54:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Testdagen_-_Barcelona/P-20160518-00170_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-18c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2511&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max fastest during first session second Barcelona-test </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2510&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The smell of Champaign has been replaced for that of gasoline in the Red Bull Racing-pitbox by now. Max Verstappen&rsquo;s race-overall has also been freshly washed and the reinvigorated, brand new Grand Prix winner got himself ready for the second day of testing in Barcelona. Just like Sunday, Max is up to speed again, and with a 1:23.267 the 18-year-old Dutchman was topping the leaderboard. That fastest time was done about an hour before lunch. Max was able to complete 65 laps flawlessly in the RB12, almost a race distance.</p>

<p>&ldquo;My first session went very well&rdquo;, Max tells Verstappen.nl. &ldquo;After Sunday&rsquo;s race, I had a good rhythm almost immediately this morning. We were able to do a lot of laps and the most important thing was that it all went without any problems. My fist impression of the new engine is positive.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 18 May 2016 12:40:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Testdagen_-_Barcelona/P-20160518-00415_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-29c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2510&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Vettel tops first day of Barcelona test</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2509&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Ferrari&#39;s Sebastian Vettel topped the first of two days testing at the Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya. Nico Rosberg set the second quickest time in the Mercedes, followed by Jenson Button in the McLaren-Honda.</p>

<p>Not all fastest times were clocked on the same compound, somewhat skewing the running order. Both Vettel and Rosberg set their top times on the soft Pirellis whereas Button completed his on the ultra soft compound.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 May 2016 20:06:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Autosport_fotos/20160517-00248_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2509&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Pirelli announces Monaco tyre choices</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2508&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pirelli, Formula 1&#39;s official tyre supplier, has released the teams&#39; tyre choices ahead of the Monaco Grand Prix, which takes place Sunday 29 May. For the very first time the the purple-walled ultra-soft compound have been made available.</p>

<p>Red Bull Racing, Mercedes and Renault&#39;s Kevin Magnussen all chose the same, most aggressive tyre strategy with one soft, two super-softs and 10 ultra-softs. Williams surprised by only choosing seven sets of the quickest rubber.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 17 May 2016 20:02:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Autosport_fotos/RDK20160222_0054-15f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2508&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video: interview with Max after GP-win in Spain</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2507&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After his historic win in the Grand Prix of Spain, Max Verstappen tells us about his race in English. Here the interview.</p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 16 May 2016 15:39:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/_P-20160515-00735_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-52e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2507&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max on his first F1-win: "Very special feeling"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2506&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Being 18 and 227 days, Max Verstappen rewrote history today: he is the youngest Formula 1-winner ever, after claiming a spectacular victory in the Spanish Grand Prix. During his first ever podium in the pinnacle of motorsports, he got down to business, and also took hold of the biggest trophy. All of this taking place during his debut in the Red Bull Racing RB12. Superlatives just fail!</p>

<p>Max on his race: &ldquo;After the Mercedes-pair crashed, I started targeting a podium finish, but I didn&rsquo;t expect to win. During my first stint on the softs, I was able to follow closely, although my tyres were going off when I was behind of Ricciardo. Then I pitted and switched to the mediums. From that moment on, the car felt great and I was able to take care of my tyres and monitor my tempo. Looking back, we had the best strategy.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 May 2016 23:56:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160515-00887_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-94c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2506&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Words fail Jos after Max wins: "Unbelievable"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2505&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>It is for Jos Verstappen also hard to grasp what his son Max brought about, after the flag dropped and he was crowned winner of the Spanish Grand Prix. &ldquo;I still cannot believe it, it is just unbelievable. Max is only 18, but the way he raced today was outright unbelievable. I don&rsquo;t know what to say&rdquo;, says Jos after a thrilling race, during which the 18-year old Red Bull Racing-driver, very skillfully, was able to fend off Kimi Raikkonen in his Ferrari.</p>

<p>&ldquo;When you see him going around the last couple of laps and you know how old the tyres are, I asked myself is he going to make it or not.&rdquo; A two-stop strategy was apparently tactical the best decision. &ldquo;In the beginning I was thinking: will it work? Everyone was thinking that I guess. In the end it did work out and I am very pleased with that.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 May 2016 22:34:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160515-00884_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-87c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2505&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Horner: "Very impressive victory of Max!"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2504&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The brilliant victory of Max Verstappen at the Spanish Grand Prix brought a party athmosphere at the Red Bull Racing team. Christian Horner, team principal of Red Bull Racing, was obviously very satisfied with the achievement of Max Verstappen.&nbsp;</p>

<p>&ldquo;A quite remarkable day for Max Verstappen who, on his debut for the team, has become the youngest ever race winner after producing an exemplary drive&quot;, said Horner with a lot of understatement. &quot;After the first lap incident between the Mercedes, we were in a great position to get some points, but to take on the Ferraris who had a very fast race car was always going to be difficult. We had to make some difficult decisions in the race, as it wasn&rsquo;t clear whether the two or the three stop was going to be quickest, so we elected to split the strategies. We felt that the two stop was right at the limit, but Max made the tyres last and didn&rsquo;t make any mistakes to score a very impressive victory. Daniel was obviously coming back through the field with much younger tyres, but unfortunately picked up a puncture with a couple of laps to go; otherwise I am sure he would have been on the podium too. But, there&rsquo;s a lot to look forward to and it&rsquo;s great to be back on the top step of the podium.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 May 2016 17:10:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160515-00765_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-62c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2504&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max wins Spanish GP on Red Bull debut: "Amazing"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2503&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen made history by becoming the youngest ever Grand Prix winner. The 18-year-old youngster took the victory in the Spanish Grand Prix in his first race driving for Red Bull Racing. Max also became the first Dutch Formula 1 race winner after keeping both Ferraris behind in a thrilling Grand Prix.</p>

<p>&ldquo;It feels incredible to win it, I can&#39;t believe it&rdquo;, explains Max after hearing the Dutch national anthem from the top step of the podium. &ldquo;It was an incredible race and I have to thank the team for an amazing car they&#39;ve given me. To immediately win my first race for Red Bull Racing feels awesome.&rdquo;<br />
<br />
Looking back on the race, Max said: &ldquo;It was a great one, the strategy was good and we were able to manage the tyres. To keep getting the lead and then to win the race is incredible. I still can&#39;t believe it. My dad has helped me so much in my career to achieve this, it&#39;s amazing!&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 15 May 2016 15:50:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/_P-20160515-00720_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-49e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2503&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max fourth in Spain: "This wasn't even the limit yet"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2502&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After finishing his first qualifying for Red Bull Racing, during which Max Verstappen sensationally took hold of the fourth position in Barcelona, the 18-year old Formula 1-driver faced the international press corps.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am very happy to be starting from the second row&rdquo;, says Max &ndash; with microphone &ndash; in Red Bull&rsquo;s busy hospitality. &ldquo;I am pleased that I was so strong in Q1 and Q2, I didn&rsquo;t expect that. I was just trying to put a fast lap together. That lap could have been better: I have only just gotten in to this new car and every lap I do, it is getting better. I really enjoyed it!&rdquo;</p>

<p>Were you not a bit disappointed that Daniel Ricciardo got the better of you in the end, while you had the upperhand in Q1 and Q2? &ldquo;No, there is no reason for that. You need to be realistic: Daniel is a very strong team mate, who knows the car longer and has all the confidence. The team is more than happy that we are third and fourth, that is just positive. We push each other and that can only be good for the team.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 May 2016 16:33:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160514-00409_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-14e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2502&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Horner: "Unbelieveable good qualifying from Max" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2501&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Red Bull Racing had a very successful qualifying for the Spanish Grand Prix. During his first outing this weekend for the British team, Max Verstappan claimed the fourth spot, not to be outdone that much by his team mate Daniel Ricciardo, finishing in third. Christian Horner, Red Bull Racing&rsquo;s team principal, was very praiseful of Max&rsquo; performance.</p>

<p>&ldquo;An amazing performance by both of our drivers today. It was a phenomenal final lap by Daniel Ricciardo, he only had one set of tyres in Q3 but he made the most of them and nailed the best lap of the weekend to line up third. Max Vertsappen, making his debut for the team this weekend, has proved to be the sensation that we know he is. He will line up alongside Daniel on the second row, in front of the Ferraris, which puts us in a great position for tomorrow&rsquo;s Grand Prix.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 May 2016 15:59:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Key_People_Red_Bull_Racing/P-20160430-00289_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-99f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2501&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max sensationally fourth in first RBR qualifying: "Podium is possible"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2500&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Just once in history a Dutchman was to be found so far up the grid for a Formula 1 Grand Prix. Jan Lammers was fourth with a ATS during the Grand Prix of America in Long Beach in 1980. Today, Max Verstappen equaled that record by sensationally grabbing fourth during qualifying for his Red Bull Racing team. Both Mercedes are, as expected, on the first row, with Lewis Hamilton on pole and Nico Rosberg in second. But both Red Bull Racing-drivers are ahead of the Ferrari&rsquo;s.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The main target was to get a better feeling and to enjoy it every lap, and it worked&quot;, Max relays immediately after qualifying with a great sense of understatement. &ldquo;And with a second starting row I am of course very happy. For sure it will take a few more weekends to get used to the car, but we&rsquo;ll get there.&rdquo; What are we to think, if you still need to get used to the car but are already so close to the top? &ldquo;Well, it helps if you are enjoying it while driving the car.&rdquo; The race tomorrow, what do you expect? &quot;First I want to try and make a good start and then from there we can keep our position.&rdquo; Is a podium possible? &ldquo;In terms of pace, it looks like it, but I don&rsquo;t want to think about that, I just want to finish the race.&rdquo; Is it not disappointing to eventually be slower than Ricciardo while you were faster during most part of qualifying? &ldquo;It was not important to be faster than Daniel. I had thought that the Ferraris&rsquo; would have been better, so ending up in front of them feels very good.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 May 2016 14:26:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160514-00333_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-12c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2500&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max pips team mate to fourth in final Barcelona practice</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2499&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen was fourth quickest in the final free practice session of the Spanish Grand Prix. It was the first time the Dutchman was quicker than Daniel Ricciardo, who finished fifth in his Red Bull Racing. Max&#39;s fastest lap, 1:23.719, was six tenths slower than fastest man Nico Rosberg who beat team mate Lewis Hamilton and Ferrari&#39;s Sebastian Vettel to the quickest time.</p>

<p>As expected, there is not a lot of on track action at the start of FP3. Most teams are preparing for a long run and are finalizing prep for a qualifying simulation near the end of the session. With the track conditions similar to Friday, it means the team are not making any drastic set-up changes.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 14 May 2016 10:54:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160514-00144_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-2e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2499&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max in P8 in Barcelona: "Happy with the first day"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2498&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After a solid performance, during the first free practice of the Spanish Grand Prix earlier today, Max Verstappen was able to continue his run, in the second practice, in the top ten very easily coming in at eighth. On Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya, Nico Rosberg was the fastest in his Mercedes. Kimi Raikkonen came in second, ahead of Mercedes-driver Lewis Hamilton.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am happy with how the first day went by&rdquo;, Max tells Verstappen.nl just after the session ended. &ldquo;We have managed to run through all the procedures, very important was being able to do a lot of runs with the car. I haven&rsquo;t been able to push the limits of the car yet, it&rsquo;s all a bit different than with the Toro Rosso, also the position of the seat and steering wheel are different. But it all went fine today, I am happy with how it went. It got better and better. Getting in to Q3 is of course my target for tomorrow.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 May 2016 14:52:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160513-00644_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-43f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2498&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Barcelona FP1: Max sixth in first RBR outing</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2497&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After a busy week in which Max Verstappen switched from Scuderia Toro Rosso to Red Bull Racing, Max opened his RBR account with P6 in FP1 of the Spanish Grand Prix. Sebastian Vettel lapped the Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya quickest, followed by his team mate Kimi Raikkonen and the two Mercedes in third and fourth.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&#39;m very happy with the first free practice sessions&rdquo;, explained Max to Verstappen.nl. &ldquo;We took our time to work through our programme and we got everything that was planned done. We&#39;ve gone through all procedures well and had a good practice start&rdquo;, said the Dutchman who felt at ease in his new car. &ldquo;The first feeling was good and positive. I feel at home in this car.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 13 May 2016 10:08:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160513-00239_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-10f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2497&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max at FIA press conference: "Very happy with chance Red Bull gave me"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2496&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Thursday FIA drivers&rsquo; press conference, looked a lot like a Red Bull team meeting with Red Bull Racing&rsquo;s Max Verstappen, local hero Carlos Sainz and his Scuderia Toro Rosso team mate Daniil Kvyat all on the front row.</p>

<p>With Max&rsquo;s recent switch from Toro Rosso to Red Bull Racing, the Dutchman was asked if the promotion posed a risk. &ldquo;To be honest, I&rsquo;m very happy with the opportunity that Red Bull gave me. Racing for a top team was always what I wanted. I think my debut in Formula 1 last year was probably a bigger risk but that went well.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 12 May 2016 15:47:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Spanje_-_Barcelona/P-20160512-00498_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-30f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2496&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a team polo!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2495&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the official 2016 Red Bull/STR teamline polo (priced at &euro; 64,95) can be won during this fifth round of the season. This polo and other Max Verstappen and Red Bull merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 11 May 2016 14:22:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/2016_Max_merch_2-2c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2495&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max Verstappen: "I think I didn't sleep for three days!"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2494&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After the announcement that Max Verstappen would be taking Daniil Kvyat&rsquo;s seat at Red Bull Racing, the young Dutchman has had a pretty busy schedule. Some of the things on his agenda included him visiting the factory of his new team in Milton Keynes and driving the Catcher Car for the Wings for Life World Run in Breda. Tonight he spoke at Ziggo Sport&rsquo;s Peptalk, by means of a satellite link. He disclosed that he was elated as well when he got word that he had been promoted from Scuderia Toro Rosso to Red Bull Racing: &ldquo;I think I didn&rsquo;t sleep for three nights!&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;I was very motivated to go straight to the team&rdquo;, Max tells, &ldquo;because you know that it is a top team and you also know that you have more chances to get closer to the podium. When I finally got to the factory, I couldn&rsquo;t stop. I have done a lot of work in the simulator and have been very busy with the team also.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 May 2016 22:30:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Max_in_de_Red_Bull_Racing_fabriek/P-20160505-00212_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-18e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2494&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max excited for debut Red Bull Racing: "Can't wait to jump in the car"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2493&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After joining Red Bull Racing last week, Max Verstappen is eager to drive the RB12 for the first time, next Friday in Barcelona.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I&rsquo;m very excited for the opportunity to drive for Red Bull Racing and I can&rsquo;t wait to jump in the car in Barcelona. I have a lot of work to do ahead of the race, lots of data to study but luckily it&rsquo;s a track I know well because we have driven there so much.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Max says about Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya: &ldquo;The main straight is quite a long one, so you need a good top speed. For me the best parts of the track are turn 3 and turn 9, as they are both high-speed ones. The last sector is also interesting, as it&rsquo;s very technical and hard on tyres.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 09 May 2016 11:43:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160429-07836_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-33f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2493&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max overtakes 3641 runners during Wings for Life World Run</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2492&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen operated as a &#39;rolling finish&#39; line in Sunday&#39;s Wings for Life World Run. During the Dutch leg of the world wide event, Max drove the Catcher Car. Every runner overtaken by the Dutchman in the car is out of the race. The last man standing wins the event.&nbsp;The idea behind the event, hosted simultaneously in 33 countries, is to run for those who can&#39;t. All the money raised will go to the spinal chord research foundation.&nbsp;</p>

<p>During the event, the Dutchman had time to answer some questions, the first one being what he thought of driving around so slowly during the Wings for Life World Run. &ldquo;I have to maintain a certain speed, starting at 15km/h. But it&#39;s a lot of fun and I can encourage the runners. It&#39;s great to see the enthusiasm of the runner so it really doesn&rsquo;t matter to me how fast I&#39;m going. I&#39;m just happy to be part of such a wonderful cause.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 08 May 2016 21:32:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_For_Life_World_Run%2C_Breda/3-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2492&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jos: "What Max has shown on track, has had major influence"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2491&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen has been a driving force behind the career of Max from a tender age onwards. The proud father has stood by his now 18-year old son, to the best of his knowledge and capabilities in order to learn him the tricks of the trade.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am extremely happy with the chance Max has gotten to show his prowess at a top team. That has always been our objective. The things Max has shown on track, have had a major influence on that&rdquo;, says Jos. &ldquo;Even though the transition has come earlier than expected, you certainly grab the opportunity. There was never a doubt in our minds: Max is ready, he has shown that. His mistakes are few, he grows rapidly and does strong races in which he scores massively. We are very happy that Red Bull has put their faith in Max by transitioning him already to the sister team.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 06 May 2016 15:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Familie_Racedagen_persconferentie_-_Zandvoort/_Verstappen_200416421-19c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2491&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video: Max visits the Red Bull Racing factory</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2490&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>On his first day at Red Bull Racing, Max Verstappen visited the factory in Milton Keynes. In the video below an impression of this next step in the Formula 1 carreer of the 18-year-old talent.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 May 2016 19:15:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Max_in_de_Red_Bull_Racing_fabriek/P-20160505-00218_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-20f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2490&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Interview: Max checks in at factory Red Bull Racing</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2489&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Following the announcement that Max Verstappen will join Daniel Ricciardo in the RB12 for the Spanish Grand Prix at Circuit de Barcelona-Catalunya next week, the Dutchman arrived at the Red Bull Racing factory in Milton Keynes to meet the team and get preparations underway.</p>

<p>Before he got started on what is sure to be a busy week for him and the team, we caught up with Max to get the inside line on his feelings of becoming a driver for Red Bull Racing.&nbsp;</p>

<p>On hearing the news...<br />
Max: &ldquo;Well, of course I was very happy. A bit shocked as well - I didn&#39;t expect it, but yes I&#39;m very happy with the opportunity of course. I have to say a big thank you to Red Bull and Dr Helmut Marko and now I just can&#39;t wait to jump into the car.&rdquo;</p>

<p>On the likely difference between the STR11 and RB12...<br />
Max: &ldquo;Well hopefully it will be faster, that&#39;s the main target. I just hope to feel comfortable in the car because that&#39;s what a driver needs. We&#39;ll find out in Barcelona. I have never driven the RB12 before, it will be a new experience and there are a lot of procedures to learn, but I&#39;m up for it.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 May 2016 19:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Max_in_de_Red_Bull_Racing_fabriek/P-20160505-00209_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-17c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2489&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max joins Red Bull Racing with immediate effect: "A new challenge"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2488&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen has been promoted to Red Bull Racing after making the switch from sister team Scuderia Toro Rosso. Max&rsquo;s first outing in the RB12 will be at the Spanish Grand Prix at the Circuit de Barcelona Catalunya next week.</p>

<p>The 18-year-old Dutchman is delighted with the challenge ahead, telling Verstappen.nl: &ldquo;The next step in my relatively short career so far, is an amazing opportunity. I really want to thank Red Bull Racing and Dr. Helmut Marko for the confidence they have in me. I&rsquo;ll have the chance to learn a lot from the top team that is Red Bull Racing. I&rsquo;m also looking forward to work with an experienced and proven team mate like Daniel Ricciardo.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 May 2016 07:30:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160401-00627_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-5c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2488&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max in line-up Red Bull Racing for Spain</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2487&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Red Bull Racing will have a new driver line-up from the Spanish Grand Prix. Max Verstappen will be joining the team to drive alongside Daniel Ricciardo. Daniil Kvyat will continue to drive for Red Bull and will re-join sister team Scuderia Toro Rosso.</p>

<p>Christian Horner, team principal says: &quot;Max has proven to be an outstanding young talent. His performance at Toro Rosso has been impressive so far and we are pleased to give him the opportunity to drive for Red Bull Racing.&quot;&nbsp;</p>

<p>&quot;We are in the unique position to have all four drivers across Red Bull Racing and Toro Rosso under long term contracts with Red Bull, so we have the flexibility to move them between the two teams.&quot;</p>

<p>&quot;Dany will be able to continue his development at Toro Rosso, in a team that he is familiar with, giving him the chance to regain his form and show his potential.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 05 May 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160317-00138_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-11f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2487&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "Max was very competitive"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2486&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Technical director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, James Key, reflects on the Russian GP: &ldquo;The race pace was there with both drivers and we had worked a lot with them on tyre management so they knew what they had to do. Max obviously had to start on his used supersofts from Q3 and we had to be a bit careful as we were not sure what to expect. Therefore, we had looked at both a one or a two stop strategy, in case he got bad degradation.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 03 May 2016 11:03:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Key_People_Toro_Rosso_2015/James_Key-1c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2486&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Franz Tost praises Verstappen</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2485&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, team principal of Scuderia Toro Rosso, praised Max Verstappen after the Russian Grand Prix for the Dutchman&#39;s performance in Sochi. &quot;Quite a dramatic race&quot;, the Austrian analysed after the race. &quot;Max was racing in sixth place after the start and was able to keep this position quite easily, creating a big gap to Alonso who was behind in seventh place. With 20 laps to go, we had a problem with the power unit and therefore Max had to stop. It&#39;s a shame, because we really had the pace to finish easily in sixth position, as he was doing a fantastic job. We will now fully concentrate on our preparation for Barcelona, where we had a very competitive package during winter testing, and hopefully we will be luckier there.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 May 2016 18:53:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Autosport_fotos/P-20160417-00067_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-7f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2485&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen's first DNF in Sochi: "We could have scored many points"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2484&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen failed to finish for the first time this season, it happened during the Russian Grand Prix. After a difficult Friday and a much better Saturday, the youngster impressed friend and foe by being briefly second in the Sochi-race. While being certain to score points in sixth place, Verstappen was unfortunately forced to retire his Toro Rosso with technical issues from the race. Nico Rosberg, once again, claimed victory with ease; his fourth in a row. Lewis Hamilton, starting from tenth, finished second as Kimi Raikkonen completed the podium in third for Ferrari.</p>

<p>After the race, Verstappen recounts with mixed feelings: &ldquo;It is a disappointing result. Not only for me but also for the team, because we could have scored many points here today. The race was good before until we ran into engine issues. I was following the drivers in front of me. We could have been fifth or sixth because from the rear there was no pressure. I was in complete control of my position on track. In that respect it was a lonely race. Later on, we saw drivers having issues with their tyres, so who knows, there might have been more in store for us. My tyres were fine. And then the engine died.&rdquo; The problem manifested itself long before it actually happened, says Max: &ldquo;Exiting turn 13, I felt that something was not right and moments later I needed to retire the car. Before that, there was no problem at all. But, that is racing: it is a mechanical sport, so these things happen.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 01 May 2016 14:33:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/01052016-RUS-4132-45c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2484&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "We recovered reasonably well"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2483&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, Technical Director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after qualifying on Saturday in Russia: &ldquo;I think this morning we recovered reasonably well with car balance on both cars compared to yesterday, particularly on Max&rsquo;s, where we were able to build in some stability with changes overnight. As a result, this morning&rsquo;s practice was a lot more competitive. We knew that today&rsquo;s qualifying was going to be very tight, with a big bunch of teams very close together behind Mercedes, Ferrari and Williams. We were confident that reaching Q3 was possible with both cars, but we knew it had to be a very well-executed quali to make sure it worked. Sadly for Carlos, he didn&rsquo;t quite get through as Kvyat just got ahead at the end of Q2, which pushed him down to P11. So unfortunately he starts in eleventh position, but at least has the advantage of new tyres.&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Max did a good job to get through to Q3, even though we underperformed in the final part of the session and we now need to understand what happened. I think tomorrow is going to be very interesting. This is a tricky track. Tyres are performing to a certain extent as expected, but it&rsquo;s going to be tight on strategy and tyre management. We know you can overtake here, even though it&rsquo;s difficult, so it&rsquo;s going to be interesting to see exactly how the race works out. Our race pace will be better than our quali pace, which is typically the case, so now we need to look at the positions we are in and how we can progress: that&rsquo;s our plan for tonight.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Apr 2016 15:22:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160301-01513_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-94c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2483&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max in the top ten in Sochi: "Very happy with P9"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2482&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After Max Verstappen finished in P7 in the third free practice, which took place earlier this Saturday, and by doing so claimed a spot in the top ten, he once again did the same during qualifying alongside the select few drivers who were to do battle for the best starting position in the Russian Grand Prix. The youngster finished in Q3 eventually in the ninth spot. Nico Rosberg, in his Mercedes, was the fastest man on track, followed by Sebastian Vettel in the Ferrari. Valtteri Bottas, in his Williams, finished the top three.</p>

<p>&ldquo;I am very happy we finished in ninth&rdquo;, Max informs Verstappen.nl straight after qualifying finished. &ldquo;Especially after a difficult day we had yesterday, I didn&rsquo;t expect to make it to Q3. The hard work paid out. The balance of the car was much better today. Q1 went reasonably well, but the first lap in Q2 was very good. That enabled us to make it through to Q3. For the last run in Q3 we made some adjustments to the front wing, but that didn&rsquo;t work out well. We will see how things will go tomorrow.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Apr 2016 13:48:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160430-00309_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-6f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2482&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max P7 in Sochi: "Balance much better"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2481&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen has managed to finish quite handsomely in P7, after the rather difficult free practices on Friday. During the third, and final free practice, prior to the qualifying for the Russian Grand Prix, he had a 1,7 seconds deficit to the front of the field. On the 5,848 meters long semi-street circuit in Sochi, Lewis Hamilton clocked the fastest time in his Mercedes, followed by his team mate Nico Rosberg, as Sebastian Vettel took third in his Ferrari.</p>

<p>&ldquo;The balance of the car was much better today. At first it was a bit of getting used to because the car didn&rsquo;t feel like I am normally used to. We were able to do some fine tuning and eventually do some good times I am happy with. The changes on the car, worked out well&rdquo;, Max tells Verstappen.nl immediately after the end of the final free practice. &ldquo;For qualifying, everyone is so close that it will be very important to be able to squeeze out a good lap.&rdquo;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 30 Apr 2016 10:47:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160429-03807_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-21f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2481&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "Day with mixed feelings"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2480&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer at Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Sochi:&nbsp;&ldquo;It was a bit of a mixed bag for us today. The track was quite low grip and we found the last sector in particular quite hard to master for a lot of the running. Overall Carlos was a bit happier: he hit on a balance he was quite happy with in the long-run on soft tyres. For Max it was a bit of a different story; we clearly have a bit of work to do tonight because we didn&rsquo;t really hit a sweet spot with him today, so we will put the hard work in tonight to get him happy and back to where he normally is&rdquo;, concludes Charles.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 14:41:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00257_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2480&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>P12 for Max in Sochi FP2: "A tough day"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2479&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen continued his Russian GP weekend with a twelfth place in free practice two. The Dutchman lapped the Sochi Autodrome in a 1:39.501. After Nico Rosberg topped the timing tables after FP1, Lewis Hamilton continued the Mercedes supremacy by setting the quickest time of the session, followed by Sebastian Vettel, Rosberg and Kimi Raikkonen.</p>

<p>&quot;It was a tough day with a lot of oversteer&quot;, said Max to Verstappen.nl. &quot;We haven&#39;t found a solution yet. It&#39;s tricky because I don&#39;t know how fast I can go into corners and if you try to go faster you easily end up off track. There&#39;s still a lot of work to do so it&#39;s going to be a long night.&quot;</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 12:59:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160429-01722_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-11f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2479&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max fifteenth in FP1: "Still work to do"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2478&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen opened his Russian Grand Prix weekend with P15 in the first free practice session. Nico Rosberg clocked the quickest time on the Sochi track with team mate Lewis Hamilton and Ferrari ace Sebastian Vettel completing the top three.</p>

<p>Theres still work to do, says Max to Verstappen.nl. The car doesnt have a lot of grip on the slippery and dusty track. The circuit is always green during the first session which also affects the grip. Well now analyse the data to improve the set-up for the second free practice.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 09:35:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Rusland_-_Sochi/P-20160429-00116_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-9c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2478&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Criticising Hamilton is too easy</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2477&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season also, he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in the Dutch daily newspaper<em>De Telegraaf.</em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>"The Sochi circuit in the Olympic Park still has an atmosphere of the previous winter Olympics. When I joined Max on his track walk on Wednesday, I noticed how tidy and colourful  the numerous flags really add to that  the place looks. In that respect I'm impressed with what the Russians achieved here. It cost a lot and it looks like the facilities arent used that often, but the place does have allure that suits Formula 1.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 29 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3023-31c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2477&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "Qualifying P5 in Sochi is not realistic"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2476&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen is hoping for a positive weekend in Russia as he described the qualities you need to tackle the Sochi track. "You're aiming to have a clean lap with not too much oversteer," said the Dutchman. "You need to hit the apexes, as the majority of corners are 90 degrees and all pretty similar. You also need good top speed and, even if we know we are not the fastest down the straights, we will be trying our best to make up time in the corners, but with 90 degree turns that is a difficult task.</p>

<p>Max continues: Getting the tyres working properly will be a challenge: it was already difficult last year but this time we can expect cooler temperatures, making it even harder. On paper, you'd be aiming to get away with a one-stop strategy, but that's not so straightforward with the new 70% tread factor introduced this season. So, on the tyre side, we will have to wait and see after the second and third free practice sessions."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 28 Apr 2016 18:22:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/16042016-CHI-3028-18f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2476&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win the Verstappen Exact cap!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2472&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the Max Verstappen drivers cap (priced at  34,95) can be won during this fourth round of the season. The cap, featuring the Exact logo, can only be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 27 Apr 2016 12:10:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/STR16024-3e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2472&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Booth to work with Scuderia Toro Rosso</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2475&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Scuderia Toro Rosso has announced that, with immediate effect, John Booth will begin working with the Italian team on a consultancy basis in the role of director of racing. The Englishman, who has wide ranging experience in all forms of motorsport, including Formula 1, will take up his responsibilities as from this weekend's Russian Grand Prix.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 15:11:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160302-00341_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-20f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2475&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "After strong result in China, I hope for good result in Sochi"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2474&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking ahead to the Russian Grand Prix, Max says: The first thing I remember from Russia is my good qualifying! It's always good to start the race from the highest spot possible and starting P9 in Russia meant already being in the point's positions Even though we unfortunately didn't have a good start in the race: I arrived to turn 1 and Hulkenberg spun in front of me, we collided in turn 2 and I had a puncture. It wasn't great, as I had damage on the car and it all got very tricky but I still tried to do my best. In the end Max finished tenth.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:50:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160414-00356_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-34c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2474&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 4</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2473&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the STR Olym-PicknMix Games: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the fourth round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:29:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00153_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-9c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2473&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tost after Chinese GP: "Satisfying result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2471&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, team principal of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the Chinese race: The Chinese Grand Prix was a very exciting race from start to finish. Both Max and Carlos did a really good start, but unfortunately Max lost some places in the first corner as he had to back off because of the crash between the two Ferraris. Carlos was in a good position until the safety car came out when he was then heavily stopped by Hulkenberg, who slowed down massively in the pit-lane and this caused us to lose a lot of places. Nevertheless, both drivers were able to catch-up and crossed the line in P8 and P9  a very satisfying result. Both cars scored points, we showed that the car is competitive and that the team and drivers did a good job. Id like to thank everyone for this and we are now looking forward to the race in Sochi where we also expect quite a good performance from our side.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Apr 2016 11:09:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Autosport_fotos/P-20160417-00067_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-7c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2471&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max 8th in a catch-up race in China: "Very pleased"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2470&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in eighth during the Chinese Grand Prix in a race that had a troubled opening. The start of the race was very tumultuous, as the safety car jostled the entire field. Nico Rosberg drove unthreatened to victory in front of Sebastian Vettels Ferrari and both Red Bulls, in which Daniil Kvyat claimed P3 ahead of Daniel Ricciardo in fourth.</p>

<p>When the lights turned green, I reacted fast enough, but the car was in the wrong power mode, causing me to not have full power. That was my mistake, Max explains to Verstappen.nl about his start. I lost some positions because of that and also during the first pit stop, when both Sainz and I came in together, I lost more. Which put me at the back of a string of cars. Thats when I thought this is not working as planned. But I remained calm, didnt get frustrated, fought my way back and overtook them one by one.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 17 Apr 2016 09:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160416-00226_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-31f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2470&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "A very eventful day"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2469&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, Technical Director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after qualifying on Saturday in China: A very eventful day. Todays qualifying was an exciting session, with a lot going on. I think we come away happy to have both cars through to top ten relatively easily but a little bit frustrated that we didnt really pull it together with the final runs in Q3. Both cars lost quite a bit of time in the third sector during their final run, which means that we are 8th and 9th when I think we couldve been a little bit higher than that.</p>

<p>We clearly need to look into this and understand what happened, but its history now and our immediate priority is to move on and concentrate on preparation for the race. There are several strategies that need to be considered given the combination of tyres available so there may be some different approaches tomorrow. Its also a bit difficult to predict because conditions look like they will be pretty warm so we will need to consider how this may affect the tyres and what implications there are for our plans.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 11:04:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/_JMP4675-10f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2469&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max not unhappy with P9 in Chinese GP qualifying</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2468&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen will start the Chinese Grand Prix from ninth. The Dutchman qualified in the top ten for the third consecutive time on a partially damp track. Pole position was once again for Mercedes with Nico Rosberg claiming top spot. Daniel Ricciardo surprised with P2 ahead of Kimi Raikkonen and Sebastian Vettel.</p>

<p>I'm not unhappy. Of course you always hope for a better result, but we were in the top ten again, which is always important, said Max to Verstappen.nl. I definitely see possibilities to get a better result in the race. A lot will depend on strategy so I'm looking forward to an interesting race.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 09:15:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00219_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-16c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2468&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max P9 in China: "Curious about the qualifying"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2467&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>During a wet third free practice, in the run up to the Chinese Grand Prix, Max Verstappen noted the ninth fastest time. On the 5,451 meters long Shanghai International Circuit, it was Sebastian Vettel in his Ferrari who was the fastest in front of Valtteri Bottas. Sergio Perez claimed the third spot in his Force India.</p>

<p>It is a pity that we were not able to do that many laps because of the rain, Max informed Verstappen.nl. As oppose to many others, I drove with a race set up. Its in the qualifying that it it will matter, shortly. I am curious.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 16 Apr 2016 06:38:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160416-00043_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2467&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "Very satisfied after Friday" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2466&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer at Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Shanghai:China is usually a real challenge. Firstly, the tyres have a very hard time and, as engineers, we are on tender hooks to see if the front-left grains badly or not. On top of this, it is very technically tricky for the drivers too and they can have a massive impact on how the tyres behave."</p>

<p>"Today lived up to those China sentiments. We saw some interesting patterns of behaviour across the three tyre compounds, especially in the long runs. We will be going through the data carefully tonight with the drivers to best understand how to make them work for Sunday. On our side we are pretty happy having worked through most of our program checklist and both drivers having settled in well. We will also be watching the weather forecast for tomorrow very keenly tonight as there may be some rain to give us some more entertainment!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 09:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160302-00334_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-19f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2466&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max sixth in FP2: "Reasonably happy"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2465&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished sixth in the second free practice session of the Chinese Grand Prix. The Dutchman trailed the front running Ferraris of Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen by 1.3 seconds. Both Mercedes, for once not topping the leader boards, followed the Ferraris in third and fourth.</p>

<p>It went ok. The balance of the car was better than in FP1 so thats positive, said Max to Verstappen.nl. The difference between the medium and the super-soft Pirellis is pretty big. To be able to instantly do a quick lap on the super-softs is challenging but it looked good.<br />
<br />
With rain forecast for qualifying, Max heads into an interesting Saturday: Im curious how well do in a wet qualifying. Its all very close but our long runs are pretty good so Im reasonably happy.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 08:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00203_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-14c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2465&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Max wants to score 100 points</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2463&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>Max sixth place in Bahrain was better than we had all expected. Toro Rosso always had difficult races there in the past. Although we were less strong during qualifying, the final result was just super. The team particularly praised the way Max took care of his tyres. But when I talked to him about that afterwards, he said: Dad, I always take care of the tyres, but that also depends on how the car responds and our strategy. Everything fell nicely into its place. That was somehow needed by the way, given the disappointment of the first Grand Prix.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/14042016-CHI-1007-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2463&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max tenth in chaotic China FP1</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2464&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen started his Chinese Grand Prix weekend with P10 in the first free practice session. Nico Rosberg topped the timing sheets, two seconds faster than the Dutchman in his Scuderia Toro Rosso. Lewis Hamilton and Sebastian Vettel completed the top three. Despite the usual suspects at the business of the leader boards, it was a chaotic FP1, which was twice interrupted at length by red flag situations caused by punctures.<br />
<br />
It's a shame we werent able to do many laps due to the two red flags. The track was also dirty with a lot of sand, explains Max to Verstappen.nl. In the last six minutes I was able to do some laps on the softer tyres but due to a small technical issue I lost some time. I think it will all be fine. The car isnt optimal yet, but we'll work on that so I'm looking forward to FP2.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 15 Apr 2016 05:03:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/P-20160415-00073_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2464&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max looks ahead to Chinese GP: "Top five would be great"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2462&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking back at the previous Grand Prix, Max Verstappen said on Thursday in Shanghai: Bahrain was definitely very positive for me and for the team and the result was slightly unexpected. It was good to score mine and Toro Rosso's first pointsat that track. Apart from that, I was also pleased that I had a very clean race with no mistakes.</p>

<p>After just two races,Max is optimistic about how his car will develop over the coming season.There is definitely more to come from the car and, at this point of the year we are still working to understand more about it, which is the same for all teams and the same as happens every year, explained Max. But the general feeling I have is that the car reacts well to inputs and we have quite a competitive package. In Bahrain we had it set up just right, so now we must concentrate on doing that at every Grand Prix.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 14 Apr 2016 18:04:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_China_-_Shanghai/14042016-CHI-1011-5c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2462&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a STR team polo!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2461&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the official 2016 Scuderia Toro Rosso teamline polo (priced at  64,95) can be won during this third round of the season. This polo and other Max Verstappen and Toro Rosso merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 13 Apr 2016 11:18:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/2016_Max_merch_2-2c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2461&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Video: Catcher Car training for Wings for Life World Run with Max and Carlos</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2460&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>If Max Verstappen or Carlos Sainz told you to run faster, you would, right? Well, thats exactly what theyll do on May 8, 2016. They join 32 Catcher Car drivers as the motivation for tens of thousands of Wings for Life World Runners in 34 international locations to run as far and as fast as they can, chased by the Catcher Cars.</p>

<p>Like Verstappen, Sainz and David Coulthard, the Catcher Car drivers worldwide have spent decades in high-speed, high-focus disciplines to prepare themselves for this moment. With endurance, precision and absolute dexterity learnt at high speed, they will slow right down to maintain a synchronised crawling speed to chase thousands of runners worldwide.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 12 Apr 2016 12:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/JS_WINGS_FOR_LIFE_CLIP_260316_0023-1c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2460&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max: "Had some good overtakes in China"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2459&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>I like China, I remember I had some good overtakes there! The first four corners of the circuit, turns 1 to 4, are a very special part and tricky to get right. Another part of the track that I enjoyed last year was turn 6 I did a good move there! I couldn't overtake Perez on the straight, so I had to do it somewhere else I got a good exit out of turn 5 and, approaching turn 6, where you normally brake late  as it's a hairpin  I managed to overtake him by braking even later than usual. It's a big relief when you finally get passed a rival and I was very happy.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Apr 2016 15:13:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/03042016-BHR-4188-36c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2459&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 3</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2458&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the STR Olym-PicknMix Games: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the third round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 11 Apr 2016 14:55:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160402-00155_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-33c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2458&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max drives a solid race in Bahrain: "Great to finish in 6th"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2457&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in sixth during the Bahrain Grand Prix in a thrilling race. Even though he barely managed to clinch a top ten position, after having good free practices on Friday and qualifying on Saturday. But with this feat the youngster gets even for the false start of the seasons opener in Australia, two weeks ago. The eight points earned, are the first Scuderia Toro Rosso has even scored in Sakhir. On the Bahrain International Circuit, Nico Rosberg won the race in his Mercedes, ahead of the Ferrari driving Kimi Raikkonen. Reigning world champion, Lewis Hamilton, came in third in his Mercedes.</p>

<p>Immediately after the race, a cheerful Max talks to Verstappen.nl: It was a great race. It is fantastic to finish in sixth here, all the more that this isnt a circuit that suits us well. It went much better, than we anticipated before the weekend. The choices we made yesterday, paid off during the race. This is a track where you can overtake very well and I had some great moves. Unfortunately we couldnt catch Grosjean anymore at the end. The tyres were working well, the car was handling fine, the pit stops and strategy were super. The whole team did a great job and I had a lot of fun today!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:29:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/01042016-BHR-2100-20f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2457&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Franz Tost: "P6 a good result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2456&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, Team Principal of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the race in Bahrain: Taking into consideration that we started todays race from P10 and P11, to finish with a car in P6 is, on one side, a really good result but, on the other, its a pity we had to retire the other car. Id like to congratulate Max and the team, because both parties did a really good and professional job, both regarding strategy and pit-stops.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, Carlos had a collision with Perez, which caused a puncture on the right-rear tyre at the beginning of his lap. As a result of this, while driving back to the pits, the floor also got damaged We therefore ended up deciding to call him in, even though originally we made him stay out just in case there was a Safety Car period. This never happened so we ended his race prematurely as the car was very unstable in the rear because of the amount of downforce we had lost. On a more positive note, this is the first time we score points here in Bahrain, so we can be happy with this, and we now look forward to China, where we expect to be quite competitive.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 03 Apr 2016 18:23:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/_JMP4659-8c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2456&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Key: "We have a little bit of an advantage"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2455&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, technical director at Scuderia Toro Rosso, commented after qualifying in Bahrein: "We knew that out of the first four events this year, Bahrain was always going to be the trickiest one for us and unfortunately this proved to be the case today. This is a stop-start track, where longitudinal performance is a bigger player than lateral performance, and we are weaker in longitudinal than lateral... So it's not playing to the strengths of our car as much as other circuits will be. The nature of this track is also to pull the field a lot closer and so it was very tight between teams today."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 18:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Key_People_Toro_Rosso_2015/James_Key_Franz_Tost-5f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2455&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen qualifies in tenth: "A good result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2454&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen will start the Bahrain Grand Prix from tenth on the grid, one place ahead of team mate Carlos Sainz. Both Toro Rossos will therefore have the option to choose the tyre compound ahead of the race. Pole position was once again for Mercedes with Lewis Hamilton beating Nico Rosberg to lock out the front row ahead of the two Ferraris.</p>

<p>Of course you always want to be further up the grid but on this track it's a good result, said Max to Verstappen.nl. It's not a track that suits our car that much so to be this close to Q3 is good. I also didnt have enough tyres to go out for another lap. I would've liked to, but in the end we can be very happy with tenth. In Q2 it's always difficult to judge where you're going to end up. You would rather be ninth then eighth so we're pretty happy with today."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 16:31:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160402-00237_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2454&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen P15 in FP3: "Really useful long run"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2453&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In the final free practice session ahead of qualifying for the Bahrain Grand Prix, Max Verstappen finished in P15. The two Scuderia Toro Rosso drivers, both hindered by small technical issues, were among the few drivers that opted out of using the super soft tyres for their quickest laps. At the front, the Ferrari duo of Sebastian Vettel and Kimi Raikkonen led the way, four tenths ahead of both Mercedes.</p>

<p>It might not look fast, but that's because we did a long run on a high fuel load, explains Max to Verstappen.nl We had a different programme than most teams. I also had a problem which meant I had to come into the pits. The team fixed it, although I'm not sure what the issue was. It meant I was able to finish my long run, which was really useful.</p>

<p>In the second half of the session the Dutchman set quicker times. At the end we went out on the softs, not the super softs like the rest of the teams. That's why that time wasn't really representative. But it's going to be very close in qualifying. Anything can happen between P5 and P14.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 02 Apr 2016 13:33:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/01042016-BHR-2007-2e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2453&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "A really interesting day" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2452&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Bahrain: A really interesting day. We started the cars with quite similar set-ups but through the two sessions we have split the cars in several ways to try to put together a picture for the rest of the weekend. In free practice 2 we had Carlos long-running the medium and Max the soft tyre. As engineers we now have quite a busy night with plenty of homework to do!"</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 19:34:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00257_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2452&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max fourth in Bahrain's second free practice: "It looks positive"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2451&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen started the Friday in Bahrain excellently. After finishing in eighth during the first free practice, the 18-year old Formula 1-driver positioned himself quite neatly in fourth in the second practice. Nico Rosberg and Lewis Hamilton were, once again, flawless and were a second up on Jenson Button (McLaren) in their Mercedes. Max was able to stay ahead of Kimi Raikkonen (P5) and Sebastian Vettel (P6) in their Ferraris.</p>

<p>This is a good start of the weekend, as Max starts talking to Verstappen.nl. The track conditions were different now and of course we need to improve many things, but it is definitely a good start. We were able to run and work on the set-up of the car, so that is very positive. Does the Bahrain track suit the STR11 as well? Its going well now, but we are trying to stay grounded because we do not know what others have tested. We will need to keep improving, just like the others. But for now, it definitely looks positive.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 18:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160401-00627_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-5e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2451&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max kicks off Bahrain GP in eighth: "Still some work to do"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2450&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen clocked the eighth fastest time in the first free practice session of the Bahrain Grand Prix. The Scuderia Toro Rosso driver trailed fastest man Nico Rosberg by 2.5 seconds. The German finished the session on top ahead of Mercedes team mate Lewis Hamilton and Ferraris Kimi Raikkonen.</p>

<p>It went pretty well. We took our time to pick up the pace and familiarize ourselves, said Max to Verstappen.nl. The conditions werent optimal because of the sand and dust on the track. Nevertheless we worked on improving our set-up. It isnt yet how we want it to be so well have some work to do. But it was good to have driven here again.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 13:45:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Bahrein_-_Sakhir/P-20160401-00477_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-1f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2450&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Criticism should be kept indoors</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2449&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season also, he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in the Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.</p>

<p>The Bahrain Grand Prix is just around the corner, but the aftermath of the first race of this season in Australia is still noticeable. It is obvious that both Max as his team, had higher expectations of the race in Melbourne.<br />
<br />
Max was on the receiving end of a lot of criticism because of his falling out with his team on the radio during the race. His remarks were a result of his frustration and anger on how the race was progressing and decisions made by the team, but I am, in no way, condoning the way he reacted. It was the first time Max did something like that and I spoke extensively with him about it. He knows very well that something like that is not appropriate and not done. It is also not professional for a Formula 1-driver. Criticism, you keep to yourself and after the race, you talk about it. Indoors, with the team. And not through the media.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 01 Apr 2016 07:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3023-31f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2449&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max happy with new starting procedure: "I can handle it well."</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2448&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>During the FIA press conference prior to the Bahrain Grand Prix, Fernando Alonso received the most question. The Spaniard will sit out the second round of the championship after the FIA deemed him not fit enough to race after his horror crash in the season opener in Melbourne. His replacement will be the Stoffel Vandoorne, the reigning GP2 champion. The Belgian will make his F1 debut this weekend.</p>

<p>Max Verstappen was also present at the press conference. After a tumultuous race in Australia, the press want to know what Max had learned from Melbourne. First of all we had a great qualifying, so we can be happy with that. But of course the race didnt work out like we wanted to. We analysed everything and hopefully we can get back stronger here in Bahrain. Even though this track hasnt suited Toro Rosso in the past, well give it our best, thats for sure. </p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Thu, 31 Mar 2016 13:58:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160320-00081_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-8f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2448&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win a STR sweat jacket!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2447&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the official 2016 Scuderia Toro Rosso teamline sweat jacket(priced at  84,95) can be won during this second round of the season. This sweat jacket and other Max Verstappen and Toro Rosso merchandise can be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 30 Mar 2016 15:18:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3025-32f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2447&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max targets points in Bahrain GP</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2446&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen previews the Bahrain GP: The Bahrain circuit has a very long straight  too long last year!  and they overtook me quite a few times there in 2015 It's not a nice feeling and inside your head you're talking to yourself and saying c'mon, c'mon!. It's frustrating, but there's not much more you can do when another car is quicker than you.</p>

<p>I also remember a lot of national flags on the left after the first three turns. I first saw them during the track walk, but then I sometimes also had time to see them while driving. Turns 5, 6 and 7 were a bit tough to get right when it was dark as the braking points change, but it's still a nice part of the track as I always enjoy the fast corners.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:42:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3030-35f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2446&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 2</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2445&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the STR Olym-PicknMix Games: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the second round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Tue, 29 Mar 2016 09:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/lekker-bezig-gap-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2445&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wings for Life brings Max and Carlos together</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2444&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>A week prior to second Grand Prix of the season, Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz made time for an important cause: Wings for Life. Both Scuderia Toro Rosso drivers were filmed in the Netherlands for the running contest, which will be held in 33 countries on 8 May. In a relaxed and friendly manner, both team mates were up against each other.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 26 Mar 2016 08:21:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Wings_for_Life_filmopnames/that-s-it-11f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2444&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max after Melbourne: "We had some miscommunications"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2443&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Looking back at the first Grand Prix in Melbourne, Max Verstappen is asked how his first race weekend of 2016 went. I think generally the week started off well. We improved the car every time stepbystep, even though the conditions were not great with the rain and in order to save tyres. The qualifying was absolutely perfect. To be fifth behind Mercedes and the Ferrari cars, that's definitelywhere we wanted to be. That was all great. I think we could be very happy with that.</p>

<p>Max continues on Laureus.com, after the interview of today: Then in the race, I think the start was good. First stint was also good. Then we had some miscommunications, I would say, and not a great finish. Did the incident with team mate Carlos Sainz lead to rivalry? To be honest, it doesn't really feel like such a thing. First of all, I'm always focusing ahead. So for me, to be honest, it doesn't really affect meas a struggle. We want to beat each other on track, but I think every driver wants to beat his team mate. And offtrack, everything is going well, so there are no issues there.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Mar 2016 20:09:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/16032017-AUS-2011-38f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2443&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max opts for different tyre allocation than Carlos</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2442&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Pirelli, Formula 1s sole tyre supplier, has announced the teams tyre choices ahead of the Bahrain Grand Prix. From this season onwards, the Italian manufacturer supplies three different compound per weekend, instead of two. The drivers must use at least two of them during the race. Like the Australian Grand Prix, Pirelli will supply the medium, soft and super soft slicks. Each driver can choose up to thirteen sets of tyres per weekend. Their choice has to be made well in advance, three months prior to the Grand Prix.</p>

<p>Scuderia Toro Rossos drivers, Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz have chosen different strategies with the Dutchman opting for one set of the mediums, seven softs and five super softs. His Spanish team mate will be able to use one more of the medium compound and one less of the softs. Of all drivers, Max is the one with the most softs Pirellis.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 23 Mar 2016 16:25:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/20032016-AUS-5100-42f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2442&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Franz Tost: "Disappointing result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2441&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Franz Tost, team principle of Scuderia Toro Rosso, felt disappointed after the Australian Grand Prix: "Both drivers did a good start. Max came back from the first lap in 4th position, Carlos was 7th. We kept a fast pace in this first stint. Carlos pit-stop went well, by undercutting Massa. After the red flag, when the race was restarted, Max was 5th and Carlos 6th. But in the following laps we lost the pace. Carlos had a lot of front locking. Therefore we called him for an early pit stop. We changed our strategy and sent him out on medium tires."</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Mar 2016 12:57:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160317-00139_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-12f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2441&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen tenth in hectic Australian GP: "Everything went wrong"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2440&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen scored his first point of the 2016 Formula 1 season. After a chaotic race, the Dutchman finished the Australian Grand Prix in tenth place. The Scuderia Toro Rosso driver was not able to capitalize on a excellent fifth place on the grid, after a slow second pit stop meant he rejoined the race in a bunged up midfield pack. At the front, Nico Rosberg claimed his fifteenth career win. The race was red flagged but later resumed after a severe crash involving McLaren's Fernando Alonso and Haas' Esteban Gutierrez. Both drivers walked away unharmed.</p>

<p>Straight after the race, Max is clear and concise in his commentary: The start and first stint went well. But after the second pit stop it all went wrong. The youngster refers to the miscommunication at the stop. The tyres weren't ready and after that it became a difficult race. I was quicker than Sainz, throughout the whole race. Nothing was done about that so I know what I need to know.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sun, 20 Mar 2016 08:12:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160320-00201_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-21e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2440&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>James Key: "P5 for Max is an excellent result"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2439&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>James Key, technical director of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after the qualifying in Melbourne: There were a lot of unknowns going into today in many respects. Firstly, it was not until today that we were able to run in dry conditions, so there was much to learn for all teams. Secondly, a new qualifying format and finally and most difficult to predict, to know exactly where everyone was, because winter testing is so difficult to predict. I think we did the right thing in free practice by trying to get some race data early on, as many other teams did, because clearly we were missing a lot of information due to yesterdays weather conditions. This gave us some valuable data for tomorrow.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 09:50:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160301-01523_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-99c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2439&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Verstappen starts from fifth in first race 2016: "Very happy"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2438&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Max Verstappen finished in fifth during qualifying in the Australian GP, his best position in his still budding Formula 1-carreer. The Scuderia Toro Rosso-driver starts in Melbourne behind the Mercedes and Ferraris, no small feat. Lewis Hamilton snatched pole in the seasons openings race, ahead of his team mate Nico Rosberg.</p>

<p>It went well. After the last free practice, during which the cars balance wasnt optimal, we changed the setup. We made the right choices and I am very happy with a fifth starting position", Max tells Verstappen.nl. In this new qualifying setup, you only have one chance to do a good lap. There is immediately a lot of pressure on you, which makes it harder for everyone. Our strategy worked out well.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 08:31:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160319-00093_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-5f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2438&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Torro Rosso behind Mercedes and Ferrari in final practice Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2437&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In the run up to the Australian GP, Scuderia Toro Rosso did an excellent job during the third and final free practice. With Max Verstappen in sixth and Carlos Sainz in fourth, the Italian squad was behind the likes of Mercedes and Ferrari as the best of the rest. Lewis Hamilton once again was at the front, ahead of his German team mate Nico Rosberg.</p>

<p>For the first time, its completely dry in Melbourne when the lights turn green for the third free practice. It is as busy as can get, from the word go. In all the commotion the teams were experiencing, in getting their cars on the grid, new kid on the block Rio Haryanto (Manor) and Romain Grosjean (Haas) ran into one another. They hit each other in the pit lane and damaged their cars.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Sat, 19 Mar 2016 05:40:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/18032016-AUS-3072-49f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2437&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max plays no part in FP2: "Tricky conditions"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2436&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Having had an almost rained out first free practice earlier today, the second free practice was also driven in mixed conditions. Max never got round to driving in FP2, as it served no purpose in these conditions. Lewis Hamilton was once again the fastest in the second session, followed by Nico Hlkenberg in the Force India and Kimi Raikkonen in the Ferrari.</p>

<p>Max response at the end of the session is short and decisive. He tells Verstappen.nl: It was a difficult day with tricky conditions. Because of those tricky conditions I wasnt able to drive a lot, making it hard for me to draw a conclusion after the first day. I hope tomorrow will be dry, so we can finish our schedule and work on the setup of the car.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 09:01:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160318-00139_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-22c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2436&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Charles: "First day back at school" </title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2435&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Phil Charles, chief race engineer of Scuderia Toro Rosso, says after Friday in Melbourne: First day back at school! I had been looking forward to this day for a while as I expected it would be the first time this year where we would really start to learn where we rank as it is so difficult to judge in winter testing. Unfortunately the famous four-seasons-in-a-day Melbourne weather meant that we didnt really get to fill in all of those question marks in either session.</p>

<p>Carlos had some problems in FP1 so we had to apologise to him after this mornings session. On the positive side we managed to put those issues aside in FP2 and we managed three decent runs with him on intermediate tyres.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 08:37:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00257_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-41c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2435&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Column: Jos Verstappen - Finally back in Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2433&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Jos Verstappen is still the Netherlands most successful Formula 1-driver. This season he shares his opinions regarding the sport via a column in Dutch daily newspaper <em>De Telegraaf. </em>Below the latest edition.<br />
<br />
We are in Melbourne again. At last. The F1-season's opener is always special. Because, first of all, it was a long wait and secondly, it now becomes apparent how the teams compare to one another.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 08:00:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2015/Formule_1_GP_Japan_-_Suzuka/JAP-240915-1002-8c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2433&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max starts off new season in P5 in a rainy Melbourne</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2434&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After a firm debut for Scuderia Toro Rosso in 2015, and preseason testing that went well, Max Verstappen finally kicked off the new Formula 1-season on Friday. The fast Dutchman finished on the Albert Park circuit in fifth during the first free practice. Reigning world champion Lewis Hamilton finished first in his Mercedes. Daniil Kvyat came in second for Red Bull Racing, ahead of his team mate Daniel Ricciardo, who claimed third.</p>

<p>When the lights turn green at the end of the pitlane, for the first time in 2016, it is cloudy and the track is wet. Sebastian Vettel is the first to venture out on the full wets. Max also takes to the track pretty early. For his first installation lap, he has gone out on the intermediates but comes back in after that lap. With a 1:44.037, Nico Rosberg is the first one to put a timed lap down in 2016.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 18 Mar 2016 04:36:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_GP_Australie_-_Melbourne/P-20160318-00059_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-3c.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2434&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Predicts Max' fastest lap and win the Verstappen Exact cap!</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2432&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In collaboration with the Verstappen web shop, Verstappen.nl has issued a contest in which the Max Verstappen drivers cap (priced at  34,95) can be won during this first round of the season. The cap, featuring the Exact logo, can only be purchased from the Verstappen webshop.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Wed, 16 Mar 2016 20:49:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Algemene_Max_Fotos/STR16024-3e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2432&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>STR Olym-PicknMix Games: round 1</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2431&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>As the 2016 F1 season gets underway, Scuderia Toro Rosso introduces the STR Olym-PicknMix Games: Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz will pick a different challenge each time and go head to head in 21 games. Before each Grand Prix this season, a new battle between the two youngsters will be available to watch. Below the first round!</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Mar 2016 11:56:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Presentatie_STR11_Barcelona/_JMP2921-12f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2431&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Max looks ahead to Australian GP: "I just can't wait to go back"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2430&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Its finally here! The first race weekend of the 2016 season is almost upon us and we are looking forward to the cars driving out on track again at the Albert Park in Melbourne, kicking-off what will be the longest season in the history of Formula 1. Max is ready to return to his STR11 cockpit, in the Australian Grand Prix.</p>

<p>"Last year's Australian GP was a very special weekend for me: I was so excited to be taking part in my first ever Formula 1 Grand Prix! The parts of the circuit that standout for me are turn 1, where you arrive quite fast  or at least that was my feeling back then, as it was all very new to me!  and it's bumpy in the braking area, so I remember that I found it a bit difficult to get the braking right for that turn. Other things I remember was halfway through the lap, when you arrive to turn 10, I could see a lot of fans there, sitting on the grass  they are so passionate and it's so nice to see! At that same point I was also able to see part of the beautiful city.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Mon, 14 Mar 2016 11:37:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/5_S0247723-9f.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2430&lang=en]]></link>
</item>
<item>
<title>Helmut Marko: "Let's see what Max delivers"</title>
<guid><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2429&lang=en]]></guid>
<description><![CDATA[<p>In an interview with Formula1.com, Red Bulls motorsport consultant Helmut Marko is asked: at Scuderia Toro Rosso you have two extremely fast youngsters in Max Verstappen and Carlos Sainz. Will running a 2015-spec Ferrari engine slow them down?</p>

<p>They are happy to have this engine rather than none at all. And I could imagine that they will land in front of Red Bull Racing at the start of the season - probably until midseason - because the power difference is still that significant. In midseason probably the performance will drop, as you cannot further develop the 2015 engine, replies Marko.</p>
]]></description>
<pubDate><![CDATA[Fri, 11 Mar 2016 11:23:00 GMT]]></pubDate>
<enclosure url="http://www.verstappen.nl/img/2016/Formule_1_Test_2_-_Barcelona/P-20160303-00114_HiRes_JPEG_24bit_RGB-19e.jpg" length="0" type="image/jpeg" />
<link><![CDATA[http://www.verstappen.nl/?locatie=bericht&id=2429&lang=en]]></link>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
